--==本字幕由 新浪微博@纸巾老湿eric 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩字幕 请关注 新浪微博@纸巾老湿eric
超体
Life was given to us a billion years ago.
十亿年前 我们被赐予了生命
What have we done with it?
我们用它做了什么?
Lucy?
露西?
It's as easy as pie. In and out, all done and dusted.
就小事一桩 进去就出来 一切都准备就绪了
Then why don't do it yourself?
那你为什么不自己去办?
The last thing the guy is expecting is a total 10 turning up to deliver the case.
那家伙绝对想不到会有个大美女来给他送手提箱
You'll blow his mind. Come on.
你会让他大吃一惊的 来吧
What's in it?
这里面是什么东西?
Sweetheart...
小甜心...
Don't get paranoid on me, alright? You trust me, don't you?
别疑神疑鬼的好吗? 你相信我 不是吗?
Richard, I really do like you but...
理查德 我是很喜欢你 可是...
I've to take care of myself right now, I got a...
我现在得先照顾好自己 我有个...
I don't know, I gotta concentrate on so many things.
我也不知道 我有好多事得操心
Hey! Hey! What are you doing?
嘿! 嘿! 你上哪去?
I'm going home because I have exams on Monday.
我回家啊 星期一我有考试
I have to shower and I have to study, OK?
我得洗个澡 还得复习 好吗?
You know what? The other day I was in this museum and you know what I found out?
你知道吗? 前几天我在博物馆里的时候学到了什么?
What?
什么?
The first ever woman was named Lucy.
世上第一个女人的名字就叫露西
露西
Is that suppose to make me feel better?
你以为这能让我心情好一点吗?
Yeah...
是啊...
- No.  - I'll call you, OK?
- 不是  - 我会联络你的 好吗?
OK! OK! OK!
行! 行! 行!
I'll be honest with you. I can't deliver the case myself.
我跟你说实话吧 我没法亲自送箱子
I've a little falling out with the guy. It's nothing major...
我和这家伙之前谈崩了 不是什么大事...
but if it's you, problem solved.
可是要是你送的话 问题就解决了
You walk in there, you go up to the reception,
你走进去 到前台
you ask Mr. Jang to come down.
让他叫张先生下来
He comes down, he takes the case, you flash him your prettiest smile and bounce.
他下来 拿走手提箱 你给他闪个你最迷人的笑容 然后走人
Look, you can even see the reception from here.
你看 前台从这里都能看得见
Come on.
拜托
- What's in the case?  - I don't know, it's just some paperwork.
- 箱子里到底是什么?  - 不知道 就一堆文件
- Yeah? Let's see it then.  - It's locked
- 是吗? 那让咱看看  - 锁着呢
and no one but Mr. Jang has the code.
除了张先生以外没人有密码
I'm just the delivery boy.
我就是个送信人
- Do you get paid to do this?  - Yeah, kinda.
- 你这么做有钱赚吗?  - 啊 算是吧
Like how much?
大概给多少?
OK, we're negotiating now or ...?
现在是在谈价钱了还是...?
No, no, how much do you get paid? I want to know, how much?
不是 不是 你能赚多钱? 我想知道 多少?
A thousand dollars.
一千美元
You get paid a thousand dollars for delivering paperwork, really?
给你一千美金让你送点文件 真的假的?
I don't know, it takes me 10 minutes and they're paying a grand and the rest is none of my business.
我不知道 总之只用我十分钟 他们就付我一千块 剩下的不关我的事
Well, it's not my business either. I'll tell you now...
好啊 也不关我什么事 我跟你说...
- Listen!  - What?
- 听我说!  - 干嘛?
We split it down the middle.
我们五五平分
That's 500 for you and 500 for me.
你五百 我五百
- Richard, I will call you.  - Listen! It is the third time this week
- 理查德 我会打电话给你的  - 听我说! 这礼拜我已经三次
I'm showing up at the same hotel with the same cowboy hat.
出现在同一个酒店 戴着同一顶牛仔帽
Problem solved.
问题解决啦
- Go! Go! I'll wait for you to go.  - Lucy, honey,
- 去吧! 去吧! 我会等着你的  - 露西 宝贝
I... I've done this a dozen times.
我... 这活我已经做过十几次了
It's paperwork! It's probably just some designs they swept so they can copy them.
只是文件! 可能就是他们为了仿造而偷来的一些设计图
That's how it works in this country.
这国家就是这样
Even my Stetson was made here. Look!
就连我的斯泰森牛仔帽也是从这产的 你看!
It says so on the label: "Made in Taiwan"
标签上写着呢: "台湾制造"
So long, cowboy, with a fake Stetson.
再会了 戴着冒牌斯泰森牛仔帽的牛仔
Baby, please!
宝贝 求你了!
Richard, I gotta go.
理查德 我得走了
- What the hell are you doing?  - I'm sorry.
- 你干嘛呢?  - 很抱歉
- What the hell are you do...  - I'm so sorry. I really need your help.
- 你到底干...  - 非常抱歉 我是真的需要你的帮助
Stop it! Stop it! Take this off me, right now!
打住! 打住! 马上给我摘下来!
- I can't!  - Take this off me, right now!
- 我没办法!  - 马上给我摘下来!
- I can't! Mr. Jang is the only one who has the key!  - No!
- 我没办法! 张先生是唯一有钥匙的人!  - 不行!
All you have to is go into the hotel and ask for him at the reception.
你只需要走进酒店里面 跟前台说你要找他
No! Take it off me, right now!
不行! 马上给我摘下来!
I'm so sorry, I really have no choice. The sooner you go in, the sooner you'll be back out.
真对不起 我真的别无选择 你越快进去就越快出来
I can't believe you did this to me.
我真不敢相信你会这么对我
- I'll be right here, you have my word.  - Your word isn't worth shit!
- 我在这一动不动 我向你保证  - 你的保证连个屁都不值!
Uh... it's worth 500 bucks, upfront.
呃... 值五百块 提前支付
You're an asshole!
你真是个王八蛋!
And you're wonderful, huh?
你真是棒极了 对不?
Miss, may I help you?
小姐 我能为你效劳吗?
Yes.
是的
I'm here for, uh...
我想要找 呃...
Mr. Jang.
张先生
Yes.
好
Who should I say is here?
我应该说是谁要找他?
Richard.
理查德
Uhm... no... Richard sent... Richard sent me.
呃... 不对... 理查德叫我... 理查德叫我来的
What is your name?
你叫什么?
No, Richard.
不是 是理查德
Richard's... uh... he's just looking for a place to park.
理查德... 呃... 他在找停车位
Mr. Jang still wants to know your name.
张先生还是想知道你的名字
Lucy.
露西
Lucy what?
露西什么?
Just Lucy. If he could... If he could he quick 'cause I have... I have to...
就是露西 他要是能... 要是能快点的话 因为我得... 我得...
Just a second while I translate...
先等我翻译一下...
Mr. Jang is on his way, stay right here.
张先生马上下来 待在这别动
Can I sit?
我能坐下吗?
Mr. Jang said you need to stay right here. I think it's better if you stay right here.
张先生让你待在这别动 我觉得你最好待在这别动
Excuse me. Regent Hotel.
不好意思 皇家酒店
No!
不要!
No, wait! No!
不要 等等! 不要啊!
Please!
求你们了!
Wait, I don't know anything!
等一下 我什么都不知道!
I don't know anything! Please! Please!
我什么都不知道! 求求你! 求求你!
No, please!
不要 求求你!
Do you speak English?
您会说英语吗?
Tambien hablo poco Espanol.
我也会说一点西班牙语
Lucy, yes, I'm Lucy.
露西 对 我是露西
It's just been a terrible mistake. I'm just suppose to deliver this case.
其实就是天大的误解 我只是来送这个手提箱的
If you lost the key, you don't have to chop off my hand, you can just cut the chain, OK?
您钥匙要是丢了 不需要切我的手 切锁链就行 好吗?
Please!
求求你!
I'm begging you, please!
我求您了 拜托了!
No! No! No!
不要! 不要! 不要呀!
No! No! Please!
不要! 不要! 求求你!
Please!
求求你!
Hello, Miss, I speak English. I translate for Mr. Jang.
小姐您好 我会说英语 我为张先生做翻译
Please tell him that I haven't done anything. I don't know anything.
请你告诉他 我什么都没做 我什么都不知道
It's all just a big mistake, OK? Please, please tell him that.
这整个就是个天大的误解 好吗? 请你跟他说
Yes, OK, OK, hold on.
好 可以 稍等
Mr. Jang wants to know what's in the case.
张先生想知道箱子里装的是什么
Well, I don't know what's in the case. Do you speak English or don't you speak English?!
我不知道里面是什么 你到底会不会说英语?!
Yes, I do! I studied one year at International High School in New York.
我会! 我在纽约的一所国际高中里读过一年书
OK.
好
Richard gave me the case to give to you, that's all I know.
理查德让我把这个箱子给你 我只知道这些
OK, please tell him that.
好 请你告诉他
He gave me a paper with numbers written on it, I don't... what is this?
他给了我一张写了数字的纸 我不... 这是什么?
It's the code to open the case.
是开箱的密码
What's really in here?
这里面究竟是什么?
Nothing dangerous.
不是危险的东西
So why won't he open it himself?
那他怎么不自己开?
He doesn't trust Mr. Richard.
他不信任理查德先生
I don't trust Richard either.
我也不信任理查德
I only dated him for a week.
我只和他谈了一星期的恋爱
OK! OK! OK!
行! 行! 行!
- Mr. Jang insists that you open the case.  - OK! OK!
- 张先生执意要你打开箱子  - 行! 行!
Please God, help me.
上帝啊 救救我
He wants you to hurry up, Mr. Jang has other things to do.
他让你利索点 张先生还有要事缠身
Can you describe the content of the case?
你可不可以描述一下箱子里的东西?
It's 4 plastic pouches filled with blue powder like a...
是四个塑料袋 里面装着蓝色的粉末像是...
or maybe a purple powder? I don't know, it looks gross.
或许是紫色的粉末? 我不知道 看起来挺恶心
Mr. Jang wants to offer you a job.
张先生想给你一份工作
A job?
工作?
I don't want a job!
我不想要工作!
If life starts approximately a billion years ago,
生命起源于大约十亿年前
we'll have to wait 400,000 years
我们得在四十万年后
to see the aberration of the first nerve cells.
才能看到第一波神经细胞演变出来
This is where life we know it begins.
这就是我们说的生命的起点
Brains in formation of only a few milligrams
从这些只有几毫米长的脑组织中
is not possible to determine any sign of intelligence yet.
我们无法断定 是否有智慧的存在
It acts more as a reflex.
它表现得更像反射作用
One neuron, you're alive. Two neurons, you're moving.
一颗脑细胞 你活着 两颗脑细胞 你动着
And with movement, interesting things begin to happen.
而一旦有了活动 就会出现有趣的事情
Animal life on Earth goes back millions of years.
数百万年前地球上就出现了动物
Yet, most species only use 3-5% of its cerebral capacity.
然而 大多数物种只使用了大脑的百分之三到五
But it isn't until we reached human beings at the top of the animal chain,
可是 只有成为人类 达食物链顶端的时候
that we finally see a species used more of its cerebral capacity.
我们才终于发现一种物种更多地使用了其脑容量
10% may not seem like much but it's a lot if we look at all we've done with it.
百分之十看似不多 但要是从人类用它所做的一切来看 已经很多了
Now let's discuss a special case.
现在我们来谈论一个特例
The only living being that uses its brain better than us...
唯一一种比我们更好地利用大脑的生物...
the dolphin.
海豚
It's estimated that this incredible animal
据估计 这种不可思议的动物
uses up to 20% of its cerebral capacity.
可以利用到大脑的百分之二十
And in particular, this allows it to have an echo-location system
尤其在于 这使它拥有着一种回声定位系统
that's more efficient than any sonar invented by mankind.
比任何人类所发明的声纳系统都更加有效
But the dolphin did not invent the sonar. It developed it naturally.
但是海豚并没有发明声纳 它是自然形成的
And this is the crucial part of our
而这就是我们今天的哲学探讨中
philosophical reflection we have today.
最具有关键性的环节
Can we therefore conclude
我们是否能够得出这样的结论
that humans are concerned more with
即人类更在意
"having"
"拥有"
than "being".
而不是"具有"
Lucy.
露西
What did you do with my stomach?
你对我的腹部做了些什么?
Nothing! Just a little horizontal slit. It's very well done
没什么! 只是一个小小的水平切口 刀工非常利落
and you'll find that in a month, this scar is practically invisible too.
一个月之后你会看到 疤痕基本就消失了
You'll be able to show your tummy off on the beach next summer.
明年夏天你就能去海滩秀你的小蛮腰了
I don't care about the scar.
我不在乎有没有疤
Is it, uh... is it why we opened you up?
是不是 呃... 是不是我们为什么给你开刀?
Rest assured, we didn't harvest your organs or anything.
你放心 我们没有取你的器官什么的
Uh, we merely slipped a little package in your lower tummy.
我们只是在你小腹里面放了个小包裹
It's a... it's a new drug the kids in Europe are gonna love, believe me.
它是... 一种新毒品 欧洲的孩子们会爱上它的 相信我
- What is it?  - Well, the scientific term is CPH4,
- 到底是什么?  - 学名叫做CPH4
which is not very sexy from a sale's point of view.
从销售方面来看名字的确不是很诱人
So, uh... we're... we're still working on something a little bit more pop...
所以呃... 我们... 我们还在想时髦一点的名字...
Any suggestions?
你有没有建议?
Excuse me.
请稍等
Welcome.
欢迎
Welcome, come on in. Lovely, oops...
欢迎 请进 很好 哎呦...
Splendid! Splendid!
很不错! 很不错!
Marvelous! Lovely lovely!
真是不可思议! 很好很好!
- How are you?  - Very good, my dear.
- 你还好吗?  - 我很好 亲爱的
OK.
好
Right, uh... first of all, many thanks for taking part in this enterprise
这个 呃... 首先 非常感谢各位参与此次的计划
which I'm sure will go off flawlessly.
我相信一定会完美完成任务
These lovely passport and tickets
这些护照和机票呢
will enable you to return home in the next 24 hours.
可以让你在接下来的二十四小时内重返家园
Now, upon arrival, you'll be taken in hand by our people
那么 当你到达的时候 会有我们的人接应你
so that we might recover our merchandise
这样我们才可以收回我们的货
and you might re-discover the freedom which you so richly deserve.
而你们则可以重新获得那千辛万苦挣来的自由
I'm sure I don't need to remind you but, for any of those who may be tempted to
相信你们无需提醒 不过你们之中那些试图
warn or turn themselves in to the authorities,
警告或者把自己交给警方的人呢
we have the names and addresses of the families of every one of you down to the distant cousins.
我们手上有你所有家属的姓名和住址 包括你的三姑六婆八大爷
So, we rely therefore, on your complete discretion.
所以我们相信你们会慎重行事
Good, anyway, uh...
很好 那么 呃...
gentleman, madam, allow me to be the first to wish you
先生们 和女士 请让我作为第一个祝福你们的人
bon voyage!
一路顺风!
Oops!
哎呦!
You gonna sell this?
你们要卖这东西?
I'm afraid it's our business model.
恐怕这就是我们的商业模式
For primitive beings like us, life seems to only have one single purpose.
对于我们这种原始生物来说 生命似乎只有一个目的
Gaining time.
获得时间
And its going through time, seems to be also the only
而花费时间 似乎也正是
real purpose of each of the cell in our bodies.
我们体内每个细胞的真正和唯一的目的
To achieve that aim, the mass of the cells
为了达到这个目标 那堆
that make up earthworm and human beings
能组成包括蚯蚓和人类的细胞
has only 2 solutions:
只有两种方法
be immortal...
长生不老...
or to reproduce.
或是繁衍后代
If its habitat is not sufficiently favourable or nurturing,
若它们的栖息之地不适合繁殖后代
the cell will choose immortality.
细胞则会选择长生不老
In other words, self-sufficiency and self-management.
换句话说 自给自足以及自主管理
On the other hand, if the habitat is favourable,
另一方面 若栖息之地及其有利
they will choose to reproduce.
它们会选择繁殖
That way, when they die,
这样一来 它们死的时候
they hand down essential information and knowledge to the next cell
会传递必要的信息和知识给下一个细胞
which hands it down to the next cell and so on.
然后再传递给下一个细胞 以此类推
Thus, knowledge and learning
因此 知识和学问
are handed down through time.
都是通过时间而传承的
OK, OK, keep calm...
好 好 保持冷静...
You have to wait, just play for time...
你必须等待 拖延时间
You'll have time to think it through on the plane... just take the flight,
在飞机上你会有时间想办法的... 先上飞机
take the flight, get out of here.
先上飞机 离开这里
That's the main thing right now, just save time.
这是最主要的 争取时间
Don't try anything, keep your cool, you're alive...
什么都别干 保持冷静 你还活着...
you're alive... you're alive, that's all that matters.
你还活着... 你还活着 只有这是重要的
Just wait, save time.
等待 争取时间
Save time.
争取时间
I'm not in the mood.
老娘我没心情
Let's imagine for a few moments
我们稍微设想一下
what our life would be like if we could access, let's say,
要是可以启用我们大脑的百分之二十的话
20 % of our brains' capacity.
我们的生命会是什么样子
This first stage would give us access to and control
这第一阶段会使我们能够了解并控制
of our own body.
我们的身体
- Sir.  - Yes?
- 先生  - 请说?
Has it been proven scientifically?
这被科学证实了吗?
Oh, for the moment, it's just hypothesis, I confess.
哦 目前来说 我承认这只是假设
But if you think about it,
但是你想想看
it's troubling to realize that the Greeks, the Egyptians and the Indians
早在显微镜被发明几百年前 古埃及人 古希腊人和古印度人
had notion of "cells" centuries before the invention of the microscope.
就意识到了"细胞"的存在 这是个让人不安的事实
And what to say about Darwin
再看看达尔文
whom everybody took for a fool when he put forward his Theory of Evolution.
当他提出进化论的时候 他遭到了所有人的嘲笑
It's up to us to push the rules and laws
如今需要我们来有所突破
and go from "evolution" to "revolution".
从"进化"走向"革命"
100 billion neurons per human,
平均每人有一千亿个神经元
of which only 15% are activated.
其中被运用的只有15%
There're more connections in the human body than there're stars in the galaxy.
人体内各部分之间的联系比银河中的恒星还要多
We possess a gigantic network of information
我们拥有一个无比庞大的信息网络
to which we've almost no access.
但是我们对它仍几乎一无所知
- Sir!  - Yes?
- 先生!  - 请说?
And what would be the next stage?
那下一阶段呢?
Well, the next stage would probably be control of other people.
嗯 在下一阶段很可能会是控制他人
But for that, we will need to access at least 40% of our brains' capacity.
但是要做到这一点 我们需要至少能使用大脑的百分之四十
And after control of ourselves and others,
在能控制自己和他人之后
come control of matter.
就是控制物质
But now we're entering the realm of science fiction.
但是这就完全是科幻小说了
And we don't know anything more than a dog who watches the moon.
对此 我们就像是犬狗望月一样一无所知
- Excuse me, sir.  - Yes.
- 打扰下 先生  - 请说
But what would happen if for some reason we ignore
如果有人能使用其大脑百分之百的能力
somebody unlock 100% of the celebral capacity?
那会是怎样的?
100%?
百分之百吗?
Yes.
是的
I've no idea.
我真不知道
Hey!
嘿!
- Hey, you speak English?  - No. No. No.
- 嘿 你会说英语吗?  - 不 不 不
- You speak English? - Yes. Yes.
- 你会说英语吗?  - 会 会
- Take me to the hospital now.  - Hospital?
- 马上送我去医院  - 医院?
我的腿!
- Hospital.  - Wait for me.
- 医院  - 在这等我
Miss, hello?
小姐 你好?
Hey, miss!
嘿 小姐!
I need help, it's urgent.
我需要帮助 很紧急
You cannot be in here. We're operating.
你不能进来 我们在做手术
Please, get out!
请你出去!
You wouldn't be able to save him anyway.
你们根本救不了他
Tumour already invaded the cortext and right side of his spine.
肿瘤已经长到了他的大脑皮层和脊柱右侧
Somebody put a bag of drug in me. I need you to remove it.
有人在我身体里放了一袋毒品 我要你把它拿出来
It's leaking.
它漏了
Do it now.
现在就做
Right. I'll just administer local anaethestic...
好 我先给你局部麻醉...
Don't bother.
不用了
Right, I... okay.
好吧 我.... 好的
Calm down, please. Put the gun down.
请冷静下 把枪放下来
I'm just going to... examine, OK?
我先... 检查一下 好吗?
- Do you mind?  - No.
- 介意我用一下吗?  - 不介意
- Hello?  - Mom?
- 你好?  - 妈?
Hey, Lucy.
嘿 露西
Baby, it's great to hear from you
宝贝 你打电话来我真开心
but what time is it over there?
你那里现在是几点?
I don't know. It's night.
我不知道 是晚上了
Hold on a sec', let me get rid of the other line.
等一下 先让我把另一通电话挂了
I'm going to go inside.
我要开始取了
I'm back, you're not partying too much, are you?
我回来了 你没有成天出去聚会吧?
You promised me you'll look after yourself.
你答应过我会照顾好自己
I'm trying to, Mommy, I'm trying to.
我努力 妈妈 我努力
Well, thanks for calling out of the blue like this.
好吧 谢谢你能意外地打电话回来
Your father is gonna be sad he missed you.
你父亲错过了你的电话 肯定很难过
He isn't home from the gym yet. Usually you call us in the morning.
他去了健身房还没回来 你一般都是早上打给我们
- Mom...  - Yes?
- 妈...  - 嗯?
I feel everything.
我感受到了一切
What do you mean, sweatie?
你说什么 亲爱的?
Space,
空间
the air,
空气
the vibrations,
振动
the people.
还有人
I can feel the gravity.
我能感觉到重力
I can feel the rotation of the Earth.
我能感觉到地球的转动
The heat leaving my body,
身体的热量在消失
the blood in my veins,
血管里的血液在流动
I can feel my brain.
我能感受到我的大脑
The deepest parts of my memory.
我记忆的最深处
Sweatie, we've a bad connection, I can't hear you so well.
亲爱的 信号不好 我听不太清你在说什么
What did you say about "memory"?
你说"记忆"怎么了?
The pain in my mouth, when I had braces, I ...
当我带上牙箍时 嘴里的疼痛 我...
I can remember the feeling of your hand on my forehead when I ran a fever.
我记起我发烧时 你手摸我额头的感觉
I remember stroking the cat. It was so soft.
我记得摸到猫的感觉 它真的很软
A cat? What cat, honey?
猫? 什么猫 宝贝?
Siamese with blue eye and a broken tail.
蓝眼睛 断了尾巴的那只暹罗猫
Sweatie, you can't possibly remember that.
亲爱的 你不可能还记得啊
You were barely a year old.
你那时候只有一岁大
I remember the days of your milk in my mouth,
我记得吃奶的日子
the room,
那个房间
the liquid...
乳汁...
Sweatie, what are you talking about?
亲爱的 你在说些什么啊?
I just wanna tell you that I love you, Mom and Dad...
我想告诉你我爱你们 爸妈...
Sweatie...
亲爱的...
And I wanna thank you for the...
我想谢谢你们 因为...
thousand kisses that I can still feel on my face...
你们无数次吻在我脸上的感觉我仍感受得到...
I love you, Mom.
我爱你 妈
I love you too, sweatie,
我也爱你 亲爱的
more than anything in the world.
胜过世间任何东西
How much is left?
还剩多少?
500 grams?
五百克?
And how long will it take for my body to eliminate the rest of it?
我身体还需要多少时间把其余的代谢掉?
To answer that, I need to know what it is.
要回答这个问题 我得知道这是什么
May I?
可以吗?
Go ahead.
继续吧
CPH4.
是CPH4
Tell me about it.
告诉我
Pregnant women manufacture CPH4 in the sixth week of pregnancy,
孕妇会在怀孕第六周的时候
in tiny quantities.
分泌微量的CPH4
For a baby, it packs the power of an atomic bomb.
这给婴儿带来了相当于一颗原子弹的能量
It's what gives the foetus the necessary energy to form all the bones in its body.
这是胎儿生成骨骼结构所必需的能量
I've heard they tried to make a synthetic version of it.
我听说有人试图人工合成
Didn't realize that they succeeded.
没想到他们成功了
If it really is CPH4,
如果这真是CPH4
in this quantity, I'm amazed you're still alive.
以这个量来说 我真惊讶你竟然还活着
Not for long.
活不了多久
Learning is always a painful process.
学习总是痛苦的
Like when you're little, your bones are growing and you ached all over.
就像你小的时候 你会因骨骼生长而全身疼痛
Can you believe I can remember the sound of my own bones growing?
你相信我能记得自己骨骼生长的声音吗?
Like this grinding under the skin.
像这皮肤下磨得吱吱的声音
Everything is different now.
现在一切都不一样了
Like... sound of music that I can understand, like fluids...
就比如... 我能理解音乐 就像流水...
It's funny I used to be so concerned with
有趣的是我曾经满脑子想着
who I was and what I wanted to be, and...
我是谁 我要成为什么样的人 还有...
now I've access to the furthest reaches of my brain, I see things clearly and realize
现在我能感受到我脑海的最深处 我看待事情清晰了 也明白了
what make us "us", it's primitive.
"我们"成为如今这样是有其原始原因的
They're all obstacles.
它们都是障碍物
Does that make any sense?
你能明白吗?
Like this pain you're experiencing...
就像你正在遭受的痛苦...
is blocking you from understanding.
它使你无法理解其它事物
All you know now is pain.
你知道的只有疼痛
That's all you know, pain.
你只知道疼痛
Where are the others?
其他人在哪里?
The others carrying the drugs. I need the rest of it
其他带着毒品的人 我需要剩下的毒品
for medicinal purposes.
作医疗用途
Berlin.
柏林
Paris.
巴黎
Rome.
罗马
Thank you for sharing.
谢谢你的分享
- Oh, good evening, Professor.  - I sweared I'll be back.
- 晚上好 教授  - 我说过我会回来
You hadn't forget your dinner tonight?
你今晚没忘了用餐吧?
I'm afraid so. I'm exhausted.
恐怕是的 我累坏了
- Have a good rest.  - Thank you.
- 好好休息  - 谢谢
You scared the shit out of me. You ring that bell like some nut bar!
你吓死我了 这门敲得跟个神经病一样!
I missed you!
我想你啦!
Me too.
我也是
You lose your key or something?
你丢了钥匙还是怎么?
Yeah.
是啊
- Can I borrow your laptop?  - Yeah, of course.
- 我能借你笔记本用下吗?  - 好的 没问题
So I spent all day at this audition, awesome.
我去试镜试了一整天 太棒了
They just have you standing around all day because they don't give a shit about your time, gabbing away in Chinese.
他们满口中文 就让你在那站一整天 因为他们根本就不在乎你的时间重不重要
Who understand Chinese? I don't understand Chinese.
谁能听懂中文? 反正我是不懂
And then they say they always gonna call
他们还说他们一定会有回信
and they never do. They don't even take your phone number.
但是从不回信 他们都不记你的手机号码
You know.Except this one guy, I bet he, uh...he's not Chinese.
你知道吧 除了一个男的 我觉着他... 他不是中国人
He works at the agency and he's cute... Oh my God, he's cute!
他在那儿工作 很帅... 天啊 他真帅!
You know, like, the cute in kinda way, like he has this thing...
你懂的 帅得很特别 有种特殊的魅力...
Oh my God, his ass...
天啊 他的屁股...
Let me get started on that!
我们来说说这个!
And you'll never gonna guess where he take me.
你肯定猜不到他带我去哪里了
Four Seasons, Royal Suite, and we made love all night.
四季酒店 皇家套房 我们一整晚都在滚床单
I'm sorry, I'm talking about myself. What's up? How's Richard?
抱歉 光顾着说我了 你呢? 理查德怎么样?
He's dead.
他死了
You guys are crazy. I'm gonna take a shower.
你们真疯 我去冲个澡
- Yes?  - Profesor Norman, my name is Lucy.
- 你好?  - 诺曼教授 我的名字叫露西
I've just read all your research on the human's brain. We need to meet.
我看完了你有关人脑的所有研究 我们有必要见个面
All of my research?
我所有的研究?
Well, I'm very flattered, young lady. But I find that hard to believe.
真是受宠若惊 小姐 但是这让人难以置信
I must have written no less than...
我可写了整整...
6734 pages. I can recite them too all by heart if you wish.
六千七百三十四页 我可以全部背出来了
Are you one of Emily's friends?
你是艾米丽的朋友吗?
This sounds like one of her silly jokes. Is she there with you?
这听起来真像她开的玩笑 她和你在一起吗?
No, I'm on my own.
不 只有我一个人
- Who are you?  - I just told you.
- 你是谁?  - 我刚告诉过你
Lucy, right? Yes, sorry.
露西 是吗? 是的 抱歉
I read your theory on the use of the brain's capacity.
我看了你有关大脑使用的理论
It's a little rudimentary but you're on the right track.
还有些粗糙 不过方向是对的
Oh, thank you.
哦 谢谢
Professor, my cells are reproducing at a phenomenal speed,
教授 我的细胞正在以惊人的速度再生
several millions per second,
每秒几百万个
and I'm having trouble precisely evaluating the time of my death
我也无法精确估算我剩下的寿命
but I doubt it'll last more than 24 hours.
但是我觉得不会超过二十四小时
What are you talking about?
你在说什么?
What I'm saying is that your theory is not a theory.
我是说你的理论不只是理论
I absorbed a large quatity of synthetic CPH4
我吸收了大量人工合成的CPH4
that would allow me to use 100% of my celebral capacity.
可以让我百分之百地运用我的大脑
Right now I'm at 28% and which you wrote is true.
现在我的使用率到了百分之二十八 你写的是事实
Once the brain reaches 20% , it opens up and expands the rest
一旦大脑使用了百分之二十 它会整个打开
and there are no more obstacles.
不会再有阻碍
They fall away like dominos. I'm colonizing my own brain.
就像多米诺骨牌倒下一样 我正在开拓我的大脑
Uh... well... I don't know... what to... say.
呃... 好吧... 我不知道... 该说... 什么
It's true, I've... I've been working on this theory for over 20 years but it's...
真的 我... 我研究这个理论超过二十年了 但是它...
it's only... all ever been hypothesis and research ideas.
它只是... 只是假设和研究想法
I... I never thought anyone would...
我... 我从没想过有人能...
You can control your own metabolism?
你可以控制自己的新陈代谢吗?
Yes.
是的
And I can start to control other people's bodies.
然后我开始能够控制他人的身体
Also I can control magnetic and electric waves and...
我也能控制磁力 电波还有...
not all of them, just... the most basic.
不是全部 只是... 最基本的
Television.
电视
Telephone.
电话
Radio.
收音机
It's amazing.
这太神奇了
I don't feel pain,
我感受不到痛苦
fear,
恐惧
desire.
欲望
It's like all things that make us human are fading away.
就好像所有人类的特征都在慢慢消失
It's like the less human I feel,
当我越发感觉不像人类的时候
all these knowledge about... everything,
所有的知识... 关于世界万物的
Quantum Physics, Applied Mathemathics,
量子物理 应用数学
the infinite capacity of the cell's nucleus,
细胞核的无限容量
they're all exploding inside my brain, all these knowledge...
它们都涌向我的大脑 所有的知识...
I don't know what to do with it.
我不知道该怎么办
If you're asking me... what to do...
如果你是在问我... 该怎么做...
You know...
你知道...
If you think about
你想想看
the very nature of life...
生命的本源...
I mean, from the very begining...
我的意思是 生命的最初...
The development of the first cell... divided into two cells.
第一个细胞的生长... 分裂成两个细胞
This whole purpose of life has been
生命的全部意义在于
passed on what was learned.
传承已有的知识
There's no higher purpose.
没有更崇高的意义了
So if you're asking me what to do with all these knowledge you're accumalating, I'd say...
所以如果你问我对于你这些正在不断增长的知识 你应该怎么做 我会说
pass it on.
将它延续下去
Just like any simple cell,
就像任何一个简单的细胞一样
going through time.
通过时间传承
Time?
时间?
Yes, of course.
是的 当然
I'll be at your door in 12 hours.
我会在十二小时之内到你那里
- You leaving?  - Yes.
- 你要走了?   - 是的
- What is this?  - A prescription.
- 这是什么?  - 一个处方
Since when did you start writing Chinese?
你什么时候开始会写中文了?
- Since an hour ago.  - Lucy, I don't understand any of this.
- 一小时前  - 露西 我一个字都看不懂
Your kidneys aren't functioning efficiently. Your liver is failing. You need to make some lifestyle changes.
你的肾功能不太好 你的肝脏功能也在减弱 你得改变你的生活方式
Take this medication. Work out. Eat organic.
吃这个药 多锻炼 吃些有机食物
You'll be OK.
你就没问题了
Last night, at 11 p.m., a woman shot a patient dead.
昨晚十一点 一名女子枪杀了一位病人
Del Rio.
我是德·里奥
我接到一个美国公民从台湾打来的奇怪电话
一个年轻女子给我们提供了大型贩毒团伙信息
- 我来处理   - 好的 交给你了
- Hello ?  - Yes, I've important imformation about a group of drug traffickers.
- 你好?  - 我有关于大型贩毒团伙的重要信息
I need to speak with someone in position of authority.
我要跟当局说话
Ah-hah, you're very lucky. There's no one with more authority in this office than me.
啊哈 你很幸运 这办公室里没人职位比我高了
But let's start with the begining. What's your name?
从头开始吧 你叫什么名字?
Listen up, Pierre Del Rio, get off your desk, sit in your chair,
听着 皮埃尔·德·里奥 离开桌子 坐回椅子上
pick up the red pen to your left and take down everything I say.
拿起你左手边的红色笔 记下我要说的每个字
There're no cameras, hurry up. I've no time to waste.
没有摄像头 快点 我没时间浪费了
Go ahead.
说吧
I'm gonna be sending you details of three people about to arrive in Europe.
有三个人即将抵达欧洲 我要告诉你他们的详细信息
Each one is carrying a kilo of drugs. I need you to arrest them and collect the substance.
他们每人都携带了一千克毒品 我要你逮捕他们 拿到毒品
I'll need it later.
我稍后有用
What form of these drugs in? Bars? Capsules?
什么样的毒品? 条状? 还是装在胶囊里?
Powder, hidden in plastic pouches inside their intestines.
粉末 用塑料袋装着 藏在他们腹内
Excuse me?
什么?
Make sure to be careful when you remove them. The product is very powerful.
取走的时候一定要小心 那粉末威力很大
Believe me.
相信我
Got it?
看到了吗?
Yeah.
是的
Good.
很好
I'm counting on you.
我可指望你了
没事吧?
早上好
德国 柏林
谢谢
是他! 抓住他!
请跟我走一趟
法国 巴黎
你好
先生 跟我走一趟
意大利 罗马
欢迎来到罗马
早上好 先生
你好 跟我过来 这边
Yeah, sure.
好的 没问题
Del Rio.
我是德·里奥
Thanks for calling me back.
谢谢你回电话给我
We got the third guy.
我们抓到第三个人了
Thanks very much. I'll send you the paper work with the transfer.
非常感谢 我把交接犯罪分子文件发给你
Bye.
再见
好的 三个都抓到了
Ladies and gentlemen, we're now beginning our descend to Paris-Charles de Gaulle.
女士们 先生们 飞机即将降落于巴黎戴高乐机场
Miss, I've to ask you to put away your computer now.
女士 现在需要请您关闭电脑
You should wipe your nose.
你该擦擦鼻子
- Excuse me?  - May I have a glass of champagne?
- 什么?  - 可以给我一杯香槟吗?
Um, yes, of course.
嗯 好的 当然
Miss, your champagne.
女士 您的香槟
Thank you.
谢谢
I'm very sorry but... uh, you really need to close your table now.
很抱歉打扰... 但是 你必须收起小桌板了
Sure.
好的
To knowledge.
敬知识
If the habitat is not sufficiently favorable or nurturing...
若它们的栖息之地不适合繁殖后代...
the cell will choose immortality.
细胞会选择长生不老
In another word, self-sufficiency and self-management.
换句话来说 自给自足以及自主管理
No, miss, miss.
不 女士 女士
You must remain seated.
您必须回到座椅上
Miss, stop!
女士 站住!
Miss...
女士...
Miss, open the door! You really have to go back to your seat! Miss!
女士 打开门! 您必须回到您的座椅上! 女士!
We're going to land soon, please, open the door!
我们马上要降落了 请您开门!
Please, say something, are you okay?
说话啊 您还好吗?
Miss?
女士?
Miss!
女士!
Miss, please open the door!
女士 请开门!
Do something, help me open!
快帮忙 帮我打开!
Answer me! Open the door!
回答我! 开门!
Miss? Are you okay? Say something!
女士? 您还好吗? 说句话啊!
她小腹有伤疤?
是的 是我们给她取出来的
- 她还好吗?  - 很好 她没事
我给她注射了一针 她一天内会醒过来
- 医生 她醒了  - 你确定?
是的 她坐在床上
就是她
- 你没铐住她?  - 必须有啊!
Miss, don't move!
女士 不要动!
- I need to talk to you alone.  - And I need you to put your hands up, please.
- 我要跟你单独谈谈  - 我要你举起双手
Did you get the packets?
你拿到那几袋东西了吗?
Yes.
是的
- Where're they?  - They're safe.
- 在哪里?  - 一个安全的地方
Here, in Paris.
就在巴黎
They'll be safer in my hands.
交给我更安全
别把车放那里 停好了
You know, as a cop, we see some pretty weird shit
你知道 作为警察 怪事我见过一些
but I've to be honest with you.
可是坦白地说
What you did back there, that freaked me out.
你刚在那的举动 把我吓坏了
To put everyone to sleep like that,
让所有人一下昏睡过去
do I need to be worried?
我该担心吗?
No.
不用
Good.
好的
Do you mind?
你介意吗?
No.
不介意
- What's that?  - Korean, I'm going to drive.
- 这是什么?  - 韩语 我来开车
Hey! Hey! Hey! No! No! No! This is a police car!
嘿! 嘿! 嘿! 不! 不! 不! 这是警车!
You can't! No, this is not possible, lady.
你不能这么做! 不 不能这样 女士
This is a police car!
这是警车!
OK, OK.
好的 好吧
伙计们 进去!
Sir, sir, excuse me, sir.
先生 先生 很抱歉 先生
I need to talk to somebody.
我有话要说
和警察说去吧
Look, I'm a German citizen and I demand us a lawyer.
听着 我是德国公民 我要见律师
我看着手术
- 去弄点吃的来  - 你这个吃货
Do you always drive like that?
你平时都这么开车吗?
I never driven before.
我以前没开过车
Great.
真好
- Hey, this is one way!  - We're late.
- 嘿 这是单行道!  - 我们要迟到了
Hey, I would rather be late than dead.
嘿 迟到总比没命好吧
We never really die.
我们不会死的
Sorry, sir, I don't agree...
抱歉 先生 我不同意...
I'm fine, fine.
我没意见
I'm going to tell them to stop following us.
我要告诉他们别跟着我们
Don't bother.
不用麻烦了
嘿 我给你买了...
Give me the case.
把箱子给我
杀了她 拿到毒品
别傻站着 杀了她!
Open it.
打开
Let's go.
我们走
I'm not sure I could be of any help for you.
我觉得我什么都帮不到你
Yes, you are.
不 你帮得到
What for?
怎么帮?
A reminder.
提醒我
Shall we go?
可以走了吗?
Where are we going?
我们去哪里?
Take the first left.
第一个路口左转
Okay.
好的
跟上那辆车
- Professor?  - Thanks.
- 教授?  - 谢谢
- Yes?  - Lucy.
- 你好?  - 我是露西
It's her, it's her.
是她 她打来了
Hey you, you're in Paris?
嘿 你好 你在巴黎?
Yes, I'm.
是的 我到了
Good, good, excellant.
很好 很好 太好了
So, look, I'm no longer at the hotel now, uh, I've come to the university
听着 我已经离开酒店了 来大学里了
where I've taken the liberty of calling and gathering a few of my colleagues to discuss your case.
我已经请来几位同事一起讨论你的事情了
Top men in their field and um... very trustworthy.
他们都是各自领域的精英... 可以信赖
I trust you.
我相信你
Oh, thank you. So, do you think you can meet us here at the university?
噢 谢谢 那我们可以在学校见吗?
I'm, uh...I'm very pleased to meet you.
我... 我很高兴见到你
Likewise.
我也是
- Captain Del Rio.  - How do you do?
- 我是德·里奥警长  - 你好
Let... let me introduce you to my colleagues.
我... 介绍同事给你认识
This is Professor Cartier, neuro surgeon.
这位是卡帝亚教授 脑外科医生
- Professor...  - I know who everyone is.
- 教授...  - 所有人我都认识
Ah, of course.
啊 当然
Uh, gentlemen, this is Lucy, the first woman to...
嗯 先生们 这位是露西 第一个女人...
I mean... like I mentioned earlier...
我想说... 我之前有介绍...
Ms. Lucy has for reasons, remains a mystery to me,
露西小姐 因为某种对我来说还是个迷的原因
unlocked certain portion of her brain
她脑部的某些区域得到开发
that offered access
可以进入
to... previously unexplored celebral zones.
我们... 未知的某些领域
She has abilities.
她有超能力
Can you give us an example?
能给我们示范下吗?
Your daughter, Gabriel, aged 6, died in a car accident.
你的女儿 盖布里埃尔 六岁时死于车祸
It was a blue car, leather seats...
是辆蓝色轿车 皮座椅...
plastic bird hanging from the rear view mirror.
后视镜上有只塑料小鸟挂饰
老大 我们有五个人死在医院 对不起
还剩多少人手?
我这边还有二十五人
该死的 她真顽强 她是个巫婆
我知道
我要亲手杀了她
There're men coming here, can you secure the room?
有人要来了 你能守住这里吗?
- I need to stay focus.  - Sure.
- 我需要集中注意力  - 好的
Speed it up.
快点
How did you manage to access all these information?
你如何掌握这些信息的?
Electrical impulses...
电子脉冲...
Every cell knows and talks to every other cell.
每个细胞都熟悉其他的细胞 并且相互交流
They exchange a thousand bits of information between them per second.
彼此间每秒钟交换一千比特信息
Cells group together, forming a giant web of communication
细胞们聚在一起 形成强大的通信网
which in turn forms matter.
然后构成物质
Cells get together, take on one form,
细胞们聚在一起 组成形态
deform, reform,
变形 再重新组合
makes no difference, it's all the same.
本质上没什么不同 都是一样的
Human considers themself unique.
人类认为自己独一无二
So, they rooted their whole theory of existence on their uniqueness.
所以他们将人类存在的所有理论都植根于独特上
"One"... is the unit of measure but it's not.
"一"... 是衡量一切的标准 但其实不是
All social systems we put into place are mere "sketch".
所有的社交系统不过只是"草图"
1 + 1 = 2 That's all we learned.
一加一等于二 这是我们唯一知道的
But 1 + 1 has never equalled 2.
但一加一从来就不等于二
They're in fact, no numbers and no letters.
事实上 没有所谓的数字或字母
We codify our existence to bring it down to human size
我们把自己的存在用人类的概念去解释
to make it comprehensible.
以便理解
We created the scale so that we can forget its unfathomable scale.
我们创造了尺度 忘记其实一切变幻莫测
But if humans are not the unit of measure,
但如果人类不是衡量的标尺
and the world isn't governed by mathemathical laws,
世界也不是由数学原理掌控的
what governs all that?
谁来掌控一切?
Form a car speeding down the road...
一辆车驶过路面...
speed up the image infinitely
加速这幅画面无穷快
and the car disappears.
车辆消失
So, what proof do we have of its existence?
所以 什么证明了我们的存在?
Time gives legitimacy to its existence.
时间给我们存在合法性
Time is the only true unit of meassure.
时间是衡量一切的标准
It gives proof to the existence of matter.
它证明物质的存在
Without time,
没有时间
we don't exist.
我们都不存在
Time is "unity".
时间才是"个体"
给我搜整个大楼 找到她!
We wouldn't be able to hold them for much longer.
我们撑不了太久的
Time to go then.
那开始吧
Are you sure you need such huge doses?
你确定要这么大剂量?
I'm afraid you won't survive.
我怕你承受不了
Some cells inside me will fight and defend their integrity to the very end.
我身体里的一些细胞会誓死捍卫它们的完整性
In order to attain the last few percent, I've to force it.
为了开发最后一部分 我必须逼迫它们
To crack the cells open to their nucleus.
击破细胞 打开细胞核
All these knowledge, Lucy...
这些知识 露西...
I'm not even sure that mankind is ready for it.
我甚至不确定人类能否接受
We're so driven by power and profit.
我们被权势利益所驱使
Given man's nature,
鉴于人类本性
it might bring us only instability and chaos.
也许这只会给我们带来动荡和混乱
Ignorance brings chaos, not knowledge.
无知才导致混乱 不是知识
I'll build a computer and download all my knowledge in it.
我会造一个电脑 把我所知的一切放在里面
I'll find a way for you to have access to it.
我会想办法把它给你
Yeah.
好的
I just hope, we'll be worthy of your sacrifice.
我希望你的牺牲是值得的
Nobody move!
不准动!
Do you understand English?
能听懂英语吗?
What is she doing?
她在干吗?
She's looking for energy and matter.
她在寻找能量和物质
And she's trying to connect with our computers.
还在尝试连接我们的电脑
冲俊!
我在这里 老大!
干掉他们
好的 老大!
你们 给我上
好了吗?
你还好吗?
快找医生 快!
Oh my God, what's happening?
天啊 怎么回事?
What's she making?
她在做什么?
A new generation of computer, I presume.
我猜是新一代的计算机
她呢?
她人呢?
回答我!
Hey, you!
嘿 说你呢!
Look, the computer, it's moving.
看电脑 它在移动
Hey.
嘿
Where is she?
她去哪里了?
我无处不在
Life was given to us a billion years ago.
十亿年前 我们被赐予了生命
Now you know what to do with it.
现在你知道能用它做什么了